<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project-rsses on Michael Andric</title>
    <link>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project-rsses on Michael Andric</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michael Andric</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Network connectivity and organization </title>
      <link>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/brain-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/brain-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work investigates the brain&amp;rsquo;s network organization. Much of this research centers on understanding large-scale (whole-brain) networks of brain function when people engage in higher-order cognitive tasks, such as statistical learning, or processing interpersonal communication. In these studies, we developed created workflows and measures to quantify changes in the statistical properties of large-scale networks. In addition to studies of functional brain organization, we extended these measures to characterize organizational differences in anatomical network of a congenitally blind population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These measures largely derive from applications of graph theory and network science. They incorporate both original code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/michaelandric/hel-con/blob/master/graph_evals.py&#34;&gt;(for example)&lt;/a&gt; and implementations of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/bctnet/&#34;&gt;brain connectivity toolbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain, Language, Cognition</title>
      <link>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/brain-and-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/brain-and-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of my neuroimaging research examines the ways that the brain mediates language and motor functions. My interest in this area looks at understanding the relationships between the human motor system, motor experience, and language processing. These relationships may enrich or even be integral to how the brain processes language and derives meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interests here also investigate figurative language processing, particularly, as it relates to interpreting conceptual meaning via metaphor and idiom. Metaphor is used throughout our language and conceptual structure. It is especially used when dealing with ideas and referential entities that are abstract and without physical form. Determining how the brain mediates these relationships may advance our understanding not only of human neurobiology, but also of human cognitive function, more generally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My projects in this area investigate the brain areas - and their relationships - that respond strongly when the hands convey meaning. This includes when the hands convey meaning on their own (as emblematic gestures) and when they accompanying speech (co-speech gestures).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Neuroscience Applications Research Infrastructure (CNARI)</title>
      <link>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/cnari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelandric.github.io/project/cnari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the Computational Neuroscience Applications Research Infrastructure (CNARI) we developed a scalable framework for research and analysis that aims to manage neuroscience tools and the heterogeneous compute resources (such as Grids and clusters) on which they can be used, to enable large-scale computational projects in the neuroscience community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
